<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-02-01T15:41:36-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">William Zhang</title><subtitle>Personal Website</subtitle><author><name>William Zhang</name></author><entry><title type="html">FTX Paper</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/ftx-paper" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="FTX Paper" /><published>2023-02-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-02-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/ftx-paper</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/ftx-paper">&lt;p&gt;Haven’t blogged in a while, but here’s a paper that I wrote last semester on FTX in the interim. I’ll write a long update probably at the end of the spring semester on my first year at Harvard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-ftx-collapse-whats-next-for-crypto-exchanges&quot;&gt;The FTX Collapse: What’s Next for Crypto Exchanges?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last month, FTX was the second largest centralized cryptocurrency exchange in the world, with over 1 million users and valued at over 32 billion dollars (Browne). The face of the company, CEO and eccentric billionaire Sam Bankman-Fried, was regarded as the golden boy of crypto—a genius MIT graduate who built a crypto empire from the ground up and donated millions to philanthropic causes and bailing out many notable crypto projects. FTX seemed unstoppable. Bankman-Fried had multiple glowing profiles about him written, including a 13,000 word article detailing his rise to fame by Sequoia Capital, the legendary venture capital firm behind the likes of PayPal, Google, and Reddit (Sequoia). The firm invested over 200 million dollars into FTX and wrote that Bankman-Fried “himself has amassed more wealth in a shorter period of time than anyone else, ever” and “[Bankman-Fried] is just a winner.” As the undisputed king of crypto, Bankman-Fried led FTX to buy the naming rights to a Miami arena, run Super Bowl ads, and recruit prominent celebrities such as Tom Brady and Steph Curry to endorse the company (MSN). In a matter of a week, in what can only be labeled as “one of history’s greatest-ever destructions of wealth”, everything collapsed (Feng and Maloney). Revelations that FTX was lending out customer deposits and did not have enough liquidity to cover them caused a textbook bank run with billions of dollars leaving the exchange in a matter of hours. Now, the revelations have proved to be true; FTX is undergoing Chapter 11 bankruptcy filings, a disgraced Sam Bankman-Fried has resigned, FTX owes creditors some 3.1 billion dollars, and the once-raving profile from Sequoia has been replaced with a gloomy message that the firm has lost all of its 214 million dollar investment (Sequoia).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sheer scope of the FTX collapse has resulted in a significant setback for the credibility of the crypto industry in general, and has raised the important question: what does the story of FTX and its collapse reveal about the future of crypto exchanges and how to prevent similar disasters going forward? On Capitol Hill, politicians on both sides of the aisle are pushing for the increased regulation of centralized crypto exchanges in light of the collapse. Ranking Member of the United States House Committee on Financial Services Patrick McHenry (R-NC) said that FTX’s collapse was a “dumpster fire” and wanted “guardrails, safe and sound ways to deal with crypto” (Wright). Senator Elizabeth Warren (D-MA) wrote in a Wall Street Journal op-ed, “FTX’s implosion should be a wake-up call. Regulators must enforce the law before more people get cheated” (Warren). Politicians such as McHenry and Warren argue the FTX catastrophe affirms that the government should play a major role by regulating centralized crypto exchanges in order to protect the safety and security of user funds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, some crypto proponents argue “the whole purpose of FTX, as a centralized exchange for tokens, betrays the impulse on which cryptocurrencies began” (Wang). They argue that the FTX collapse shows that centralized exchanges inherently cannot be trusted, and instead advocate for the usage of decentralized exchanges—automated crypto exchanges governed by codified contracts. Alex Andryunion, the CEO of Gotbit, a leading crypto consultancy, says that “decentralization is on the winning side … many of our clients [after the FTX collapse] have asked to withdraw funds from a centralized exchange and switch the market control of their tokens to [decentralized exchanges] only” (Rapoza).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the government regulation of centralized exchanges appears to be able to prevent future disasters such as the FTX collapse, the story of FTX instead shows that centralized crypto exchanges are built on a core fallacy—even with regulation, they destroy the fundamental ethos of crypto being a decentralized currency. Despite the appeal of decentralized exchanges in the face of the FTX collapse, ultimately the crash reveals something even broader: crypto exchanges in and of themselves, whether regulated or decentralized, should not be trusted nor used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Crypto frauds have been running rampant ever since the inception of cryptocurrency as a concept: a fully decentralized peer-to-peer digital currency free from the oversight of a central bank or government. Because these digital currencies are difficult for users to manage and trade themselves, centralized solutions such as FTX have emerged to provide an easy way for users to store and exchange crypto on their platform instead (Smith). These centralized exchanges work by holding crypto on behalf of users so they can easily interact with their funds, with the understanding that users can withdraw their funds from the exchange into their own custody whenever they please. These exchanges are known as being “centralized” because all transactions are processed and verified by the exchange itself, rather than being distributed across a network of users. This means that the exchange has full control over the transactions that take place on its platform, which can make it easier for the exchange to provide services like wallet management or fiat currency conversion. However, it also means that the exchange is a single point of failure and can be more vulnerable to security breaches or other problems (BeInCrypto). Decentralized exchanges, on the other hand, are built on blockchain technology and do not have a central authority controlling them. Instead, transactions are processed and verified by a network of users, which makes the exchange more secure and resistant to tampering or censorship. The network of users agree on “smart contracts”, self-executing contracts with the terms of the agreement between buyer and seller being directly written into lines of code. However, they can be, understandably, more complex to use and may not offer the same range of features as centralized exchanges (BeInCrypto). In the case of FTX, the company was a centralized crypto exchange with a centralized point of failure, namely Sam Bankman-Fried himself. The spark behind the catastrophe was Bankman-Fried taking control of customer deposits and secretly lending them out to his trading firm Alameda Research, hidden in part due to FTX’s “complete failure of corporate controls and such a complete absence of trustworthy financial information” as described by FTX’s bankruptcy court filings (Jay III).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At a first glance, the FTX collapse may suggest that government regulation of centralized crypto exchanges is the perfect method to protect the crypto industry moving forward. However, by digging deeper into the weeds of FTX’s involvement on Capitol Hill, it is evident that even with regulation, centralized crypto exchanges fundamentally destroy the ethos of cryptocurrency being a decentralized store of value. Following FTX’s collapse, a coalition of bipartisan support from politicians overwhelmingly have advocated for bills to be passed enabling the regulation of said exchanges. They have essentially banded together, saying that “now more than ever, it is clear that there are major consequences when cryptocurrency entities operate without robust federal oversight and protections for customers” (Waters D-C) and that “by going for months and months without addressing the digital asset industry that has grown so quickly, we have put ourselves at a regulatory disadvantage in dealing with the lack of consumer protections.” (Gillibrand D-NY).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although when taken at face value these statements seem to hint towards the safe regulation of centralized crypto exchanges following the FTX collapse, the truth is far from what meets the eye. Looking more closely into FTX’s story, a chilling bombshell emerges—leading up to FTX’s implosion, Sam Bankman-Fried, on behalf of FTX, heavily lobbied in support of government regulation. Bankman-Fried boasted that FTX was the “most regulated” crypto exchange and actively invited authorities to scrutinize the company (Fox Business). Crypto regulation bills that landed on the floor of the Senate well before the collapse have been supported by Sam Bankman-Fried in the past - in fact, the Commodity Futures Trading Commision (CFTC) had met with FTX officials 10 times over the past couple of years. During a hearing after the collapse, the director of the CFTC had to “wiggle around questions about the number of meetings and communications he had with Bankman-Fried.” (Barr). It is quite simply astonishing that the CEO of the FTX itself actively supported and invited more regulation to his company while it was undergoing egregious acts of malpractice. 
There is only one logical explanation for this engagement—Sam Bankman-Fried, put simply, had some degree of control with the United States government in regards to regulation. He appeared honest and open about FTX to the public, while lobbying lawmakers to view FTX without any suspicion. This notion is supported by a text exchange between Vox and Bankman-Fried immediately following the collapse of FTX. When asked if his support of regulation was “just PR”, he replied “yeah, just PR … fuck regulators … they make everything worse … they don’t protect customers at all.” (Piper). The FTX debacle shows that centralized crypto exchange regulation, while seemingly a useful, clear, and safe response from the outside, is simply a catalyst for deep-pocketed companies such as FTX to shield themselves and hide their negligence. Sam Bankman-Fried did not want regulation to protect his users, and instead wanted regulation to protect FTX’s competitive advantage. What FTX was able to do from a regulatory standpoint suggests that influencing crypto regulators on Capitol Hill can and will continue to happen, even with increased regulation. This is demonstrated through the fact that even before the FTX collapse and politicians began banding together to call for regulation, there had already been regulation bills in place which were heavily influenced by people such as Bankman-Fried—the FTX story suggests that this was not an isolated incident and the influence will not stop. The sheer scope of what FTX grew to become and how easy it was for Bankman-Fried to manipulate regulators implies that even with more strict regulations, there will be more of these incidents in the future, with new CEOs and new centralized exchanges that come in right where FTX left off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking this crux a step further, the FTX story reveals dirty CEOs and lobbyists pushing to change regulations to their benefit, leading to the conclusion that the landscape of centralized crypto exchanges stands to be no different than traditional financial institutions ripe with malfeasance. For example, in the 2008 financial crisis, the now-defunct Lehman Brothers was reported to be a “big player in donating to political campaigns, which could be a plus if the struggling investment bank needs federal help” (Drawbaugh). In an eerily similar fashion, FTX executives donated over 70 million dollars to political campaigns, with Sam Bankman-Fried being the overall second highest liberal donor just weeks before FTX’s bankruptcy (Biron). In that sense, the FTX collapse shows how centralized crypto exchanges destroy the ethos of cryptocurrency, as mentioned earlier, “a fully decentralized peer-to-peer digital currency free from the oversight of a central bank or government.” By centralized exchanges engaging in the same egregious rule-bending and corruption that plague traditional financial institutions under the oversight of the government, this shining light of crypto is extinguished. Ultimately, the FTX regulatory landscape suggests that any attempts to regulate crypto fundamentally defeats the purpose of crypto itself - there is no need for cryptocurrencies other than the fact that it is decentralized, open, anonymous, and digital. Attempting to remove these freedoms that crypto offers is the equivalent of stripping the core beliefs of the crypto movement itself to the point where cryptocurrencies are the same as a digital fiat dollar equivalent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outside of Capitol Hill, some proponents of crypto argue instead that the FTX collapse shows decentralized exchanges should pave the way for the future of crypto. While this may seem as a formidable prospect, in reality the story of FTX shows how deeply intertwined decentralized exchanges are with similar instances of fraud and deception. Coindesk, the very same new site which published internal balance sheets that sparked the entire FTX collapse, published an op-ed detailing that “the meltdown of Sam Bankman-Fried’s crypto trading empire could not, and would not, have happened to a decentralized and transparent protocol” and “despite sell-offs, [decentralized exchanges] have been functioning smoothly … if that isn’t consumer protection, I don’t know what is” (Cassatt). Supporters of decentralized exchanges have distanced themselves from the FTX collapse by establishing that FTX was not a decentralized exchange, and if it was indeed decentralized, fraud would have been impossible. Proponents argue that the FTX implosion strengthens the mantra that “code is law” when interacting with decentralized exchanges—there should be no regulation or government oversight when code is what is controlling funds in these exchanges (Yeung).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In reality, centralized exchanges such as FTX and the people behind them have much more leverage in decentralized exchanges than what proponents of crypto acknowledge. The fallout after the FTX collapse has not only affected FTX and its users, but also adjacent decentralized exchange communities in which FTX and Sam Bankman Fried were involved. Just this week, Bloomberg reported that “contagion from the messy implosion of Sam Bankman-Fried’s crypto empire is spilling into the world of decentralized finance”—after a hedge fund went under due to the FTX collapse, the entirety of their 850 million dollar stake on the decentralized exchange Maple was put in jeopardy (Shukla and Nicolle). Not only did the FTX collapse negatively affect individual decentralized exchanges, but entire decentralized finance communities as a whole. The most shining example is the case of Solana, a decentralized finance ecosystem which Sam Bankman-Fried and FTX had invested in and promoted so heavily to the point where some tokens on the platform were known as “Sam coins” (Protos). Solana’s trading volume cratered 75% to under 20 million dollars following the crash, and to make the situation catastrophically worse, another bombshell revealed that the supposedly decentralized ecosystem was “not controlled by [the community], but by a private key connected to FTX” (Elliot). These revelations regarding the collapse show that FTX was so deeply, horrifically entrenched in the business of some decentralized exchanges. This suggests that so-called “decentralized” exchanges are not at all what they bill themselves to be. Instead of being free from oversight and centralized control, in some instances they are simply a facade to even more fraudulent behavior as demonstrated by the FTX implosion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even in cases where decentralized exchanges fall outside the direct reach of centralized exchanges such as FTX, the argument that decentralized exchanges fully protect user funds in lieu of the FTX collapse is simply false. In what has been somewhat buried under the media reporting of the implosion itself, after FTX filed for bankruptcy, it was also subject to a hack which drained over 600 million dollars from their leftover holdings (Powell and Leggatt). Because a truly decentralized exchange is not subject to the centralized control of assets, using such an exchange would prevent the Bankman-Fried scenario of secretly lending out customer deposits. Despite this, these decentralized exchanges are still extremely exposed to being hacked in a similar fashion to FTX. For example, a 600 million dollar attack on the decentralized Ronin crypto exchange occurred just earlier this year (Nicolle), and a similar exchange called Mango Markets was hacked by a teen crypto vigilante for over 67 million dollars just last month (Roberts). These hacks and similar hacks on decentralized exchanges pose a significant threat to the security of these platforms, which renders them futile as a solution to the FTX collapse. The FTX story reiterates the fact that hacks of significant magnitude can target both centralized and decentralized exchanges alike, with no guarantee on the safety of user funds.
The story of FTX and its collapse reveals that the two viewpoints for the future of crypto exchanges—one that advocates for government regulation of centralized crypto exchanges, and one that advocates for the usage of decentralized exchanges—are fundamentally flawed. On one hand, FTX’s collapse proved that government regulation was not only ineffective against fraud, but also that centralized exchanges fundamentally went against the core principle of crypto being a decentralized currency free from central bank and government oversight. On the other hand, FTX’s story exposes that some decentralized exchanges are not as decentralized as they seem, and that they are still susceptible to some of the same hacks that have plagued FTX. With the irreconcilable flaws of both centralized and decentralized exchanges brought to light, the FTX disaster implies that only one viable solution for the future of crypto remains—to not use exchanges in the first place, and instead go back to the roots of self-custody with users storing their own cryptocurrency in their own wallets on their own devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;works-cited&quot;&gt;Works Cited&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Barr, Kyle. “U.S. Senate Is Still Confused about How to Regulate Crypto after FTX Collapse.” MSN, https://www.msn.com/en-us/news/politics/us-senate-is-still-confused-about-how-to-regulate-crypto-after-ftx-collapse/ar-AA14N5XO.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Biron, Bethany. “FTX Founder Sam Bankman-Fried Donated $40 Million to Political Campaigns Leading into the Midterms, Leaving Some Concerned about Crypto’s Place in Washington, Report Says.” Yahoo! News, Yahoo!, https://news.yahoo.com/ftx-founder-sam-bankman-fried-210458468.html.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Browne, Ryan. “Cryptocurrency Exchange FTX Hits $32 Billion Valuation despite Bear Market Fears.” CNBC, CNBC, 1 Feb. 2022, https://www.cnbc.com/2022/01/31/crypto-exchange-ftx-valued-at-32-billion-amid-bitcoin-price-plunge.html.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cassatt, Amanda. “FTX Showed the Problems of Centralized Finance, and Proved the Need for Defi.” CoinDesk Latest Headlines RSS, CoinDesk, 11 Nov. 2022, https://www.coindesk.com/layer2/2022/11/11/
ftx-showed-the-problems-of-centralized-finance-and-proved-the-need-for-defi/.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Cefi vs. Defi: Everything You Need to Know.” BeInCrypto, 22 Nov. 2022, https://beincrypto.com/learn/cefi-vs-defi/.
Drawbaugh, Kevin. “Lehman Donors Give Generously to Political Candidates.” Reuters, Thomson Reuters, 11 Sept. 2008, https://www.reuters.com/article/us-lehman-campaign-giving-idINN1127961720080911.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Elliott, Stacy. “Life after FTX: How Solana Defi Is Starting over-without SBF’s Serum.” Yahoo!, Yahoo!, https://www.yahoo.com/now/life-ftx-solana-defi-starting-223848156.html.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feng, Venus, and Tom Maloney. “Sam Bankman-Fried’s Net Worth Goes from $16 Billion to Zero after FTX Collapse.” Bloomberg.com, Bloomberg, 11 Nov. 2022, https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2022-11-11/sam-bankman-fried-s-assets-go-from-16-billion-to-zero-after-ftx-collapse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Waters, and Gillibrand. “Official FTX Statement.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“FTX.” Sequoia Capital US/Europe, 1 Dec. 2022, https://www.sequoiacap.com/article/sam-bankman-fried-spotlight/.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Piper, Kelsey. “Sam Bankman-Fried Tries to Explain Himself.” Vox, Vox, 16 Nov. 2022, https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/23462333/sam-bankman-fried-ftx-cryptocurrency-effective-altruism-crypto-bahamas-philanthropy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Powell, Farran, and Johanna Leggatt. “FTX Collapse: From Hero to Zero in 24 Hours.” Forbes, Forbes Magazine, 8 Dec. 2022, https://www.forbes.com/advisor/au/investing/cryptocurrency/ftx-from-hero-to-zero-in-24-hours/.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rapoza, Kenneth. “The FTX Crisis Brought Investors to Decentralized Exchanges. Here’s Why They Might Leave.” Forbes, Forbes Magazine, 5 Dec. 2022, https://www.forbes.com/sites/kenrapoza/2022/12/04/the-ftx-crisis-brought-investors-to-decentralized-exchanges-heres-why-they-might-leave/?sh=33770b259ebc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ray, John J. “Declaration of John J. Ray III In Support Of Chapter II Petitions and First Day Pleadings.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reuters. “How FTX Bought Its Way to Become the ‘Most Regulated’ Crypto Exchange.” Fox Business, Fox Business, 18 Nov. 2022, https://www.foxbusiness.com/markets/how-ftx-bought-its-way-to-become-the-most-regulated-crypto-exchange.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Roberts. A Solana Hacker Calls $67M He Stole from the Mango Platform a ‘Profitable Trading Strategy’. Fortune Crypto (Online).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shukla, Sidhartha, and Emily Nicolle. “Crypto Fund Orthogonal Defaults on $36 Million Debt as FTX Contagion Spreads.” Bloomberg.com, Bloomberg, 6 Dec. 2022, https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2022-12-06/crypto-fund-orthogonal-defaults-on-36-million-debt-as-ftx-contagion-spreads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nicolle. Massive Crypto Hacks Test ‘Code is Law’ Ethos. Bloomberg Crypto (Online).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Smith, Timothy. “What Is FTX?” Investopedia, Investopedia, 8 Dec. 2022, https://www.investopedia.com/ftx-exchange-5200842.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Solana’s Close Ties to FTX Cause Financial and Structural Damage.” Protos, 18 Nov. 2022, https://protos.com/solanas-close-ties-to-ftx-cause-financial-and-structural-damage/.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Tom Brady, Steph Curry and Kevin O’Leary Set to Lose Big from FTX Bankruptcy Filing.” MSN, https://www.msn.com/en-us/money/companies/tom-brady-steph-curry-and-kevin-o-leary-set-to-lose-big-from-ftx-bankruptcy-filing/ar-AA140ULU.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wang, Jeffrey. “Opinion : the Future of Cryptocurrency after FTX and Sam Bankman-Fried.” The Wall Street Journal, Dow Jones &amp;amp; Company, 6 Dec. 2022, https://www.wsj.com/articles/the-future-of-cryptocurrency-after-ftx-and-sam-bankman-fried-investors-exchange-value-money-11670353419.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Warren, Elizabeth. “Opinion : Regulate Crypto or It’ll Take down the Economy.” The Wall Street Journal, Dow Jones &amp;amp; Company, 23 Nov. 2022, https://www.wsj.com/articles/regulate-crypto-or-itll-take-down-the-economy-fraud-reporting-know-your-customer-loophole-energy-disclosure-ftx-bankman-fried-ftx-11669123750.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wright, Turner. “Crypto Skeptic Brad Sherman: Federal Financial Regulators ‘Sound like Sam Bankman-Fried’.” Cointelegraph, Cointelegraph, 16 Nov. 2022, https://cointelegraph.com/news/crypto-skeptic-brad-sherman-federal-financial-regulators-sound-like-sam-bankman-fried.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yeung. (2019). Regulation by blockchain: The emerging battle for supremacy between the Code of Law and Code as Law. Modern Law Review, 82(2), 207–239.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>William Zhang</name></author><summary type="html">Haven’t blogged in a while, but here’s a paper that I wrote last semester on FTX in the interim. I’ll write a long update probably at the end of the spring semester on my first year at Harvard.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">California Summer: 1517 + SPARC + EAG + Vibing</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/california-reflections" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="California Summer: 1517 + SPARC + EAG + Vibing" /><published>2022-08-02T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-08-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/california-reflections</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/california-reflections">&lt;p&gt;On July 14th, I hopped on a plane from Newark to San Diego and began my California adventures &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. I took an overnight bus from San Diego to San Francisco a couple of days later, and then took the BART to Berkeley where I stayed for 2 weeks. While at Berkeley, I went on a couple of day trips to nearby cities like Alameda and Oakland. I went back to San Francisco for a night before taking a plane to Santa Barbara, stayed there for a night and then took a bus to Los Angeles where I’m crashing for two nights before heading back to New York.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;1517-summit&quot;&gt;1517 Summit&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I finally met my good friends Nima, Calix, and Kevin IRL for the first time, and the amazing folks at 1517 hooked us up with an awesome hotel room overlooking the water. We did a shit ton of really fun stuff like jetskiing and late night workouts. The summit itself was pretty enjoyable, however I wish the alpha density was higher. I met some crazy smart and ambitious people but also people who I honestly believe had the intellectual capacity of a vegetable. In general, the talks were very interesting, however the breakout sessions were a bit less so. Still a great trip to San Diego nonetheless and I would 100% go again!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;sparc&quot;&gt;SPARC&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember mentioning that I was going to SPARC on my Twitter but I’m not sure if the news made it into my blog. Anyways, SPARC is the “Summer Program for Applied Rationality and Cognition”, also known as “group therapy for nerdy kids” according to Yan Zhang, the director of SPARC. It’s a fully-funded competitive summer program that usually attracts top academic olympians (think USAMO, MOP, IMO, USACO campers, etc.) and some startup + research people (I fall into the latter category).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going into SPARC I definitely felt a little bit different. I’m certain that everyone there was smarter than me in some way or another. However, I quickly settled in to the environment, made some lifelong friends, and had some really insightful/reflective 1 on 1 conversations. The classes were also super interesting, and I really appreciated the high degree of freedom we were given. There were no expectations to attend classes, afternoon activities, or anything to that matter. We were really given the autonomy to do whatever we wanted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really can’t put into words how fucking fun SPARC was. My friend group that I hung out the most with, the “Fine Nine”, consisted of three MOPers, one UAEMOer, three USAMOers, some others but you get the idea. And then there was me, a proud AMC10er LOL. Thank god we didn’t talk about math all of the time, the closest we came to that was me creating my first AOPS account and trolling the SPARC thread (follow me please, @AsianHackerasi, the “asi” was a typo but I can’t change it anymore).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got to live with people who were actually cracked at STEM, startups, hackathons, research, etc. - even philosophers! My favorite people included the &lt;strong&gt;Fine Nine&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;ML&lt;/strong&gt; (suitemate, baller, and Exeter kid), &lt;strong&gt;AA&lt;/strong&gt; (roommate, Indian team on the International Philosophy Olympiad which is a story in and of itself, shitload of hackathon wins, and a complete troll), &lt;strong&gt;UG&lt;/strong&gt; (suitemate, Google Code-in winner in my cohort, we did a lot of stuff together over the years), and so many others. I really vibed with everyone so I’ll stop here but seriously everyone there was awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of my favorite memories from SPARC include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Guest speakers Michael Gao and Tina Ju on breaking through mental limits and doing the impossible.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I kid you not, playing poker every night until 2AM. I religiously studied this game and it got to the point where other campers and even instructors were hiring poker coaches, buying the “David Nagru” poker masterclass, and taking the MIT Poker Theory and Analytics OCW class. I’m very grateful for the opportunity to play 50 hours of poker with geniuses and getting whooped most of the time. Hopefully I can win money with regular plebeians the next time I play :)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Playing a variant of “A Quiet Year” with Yan, &lt;strong&gt;ML&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;NR&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;RS&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;SW&lt;/strong&gt;, and  &lt;strong&gt;UG&lt;/strong&gt;. Sooo good.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Game theory, betting markets, and calibration classes were top notch.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The best hikes I’ve even been on, extremely strenuous but worth every step. We went mainly on the Berkeley fire trails. Got to hang out and talk life, girls, tech, and research with my good friends &lt;strong&gt;JA&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;AZ&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;RA&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Late night guy chats with &lt;strong&gt;AA&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;ML&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;AW&lt;/strong&gt;, and some others.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Top Dog and boba runs (I can eat 6 hot dogs at once, and if you ever go to Top Dog in Berkeley make sure to get the garlic frankfurter).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Beach trips, volleyball, music, spikeball, pool, movies, stadium sneakery, and my first all-nighter with &lt;strong&gt;LS&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;RF&lt;/strong&gt; (won’t be doing that again anytime soon).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SPARC was the absolute best and I can’t recommend it enough. Shoutout to &lt;strong&gt;CP&lt;/strong&gt; for recruiting me to the program, I wouldn’t have applied if it hadn’t been for the personalized email and reminders. I highly recommend this program for really anyone interested in STEM, rationality, cognition, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still feel like I’m not doing SPARC enough justice, but just know it’s more than worth it to attend :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;eag&quot;&gt;EAG&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My friends have been hyping up EAG conferences for a while, so I finally decided to apply. Happy that I got in, and EAG SF was quite the interesting experience. For starters, I didn’t receive SwapCard access until the day I went there, so couldn’t schedule 1 on 1s. A lot of the time was just talking to random people and getting to know the gist of EA a bit better. The food was vegan btw smh. All in all, I am much more pro-EA compared to before the conference, but I still have concerns about funding methods for longtermism (AI safety, alignment, interpretability). I’ll be attending some more EAG conferences in the near future, where hopefully I’ll get SwapCard access on time and can schedule some useful 1 on 1s!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;vibing-santa-barbara-and-la&quot;&gt;Vibing: Santa Barbara and LA&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quality time surfing, beach walking, and eating amazing food in Santa Barbara and LA. Hanging out with friends and enjoying the last few weeks of summer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;closing-thoughts&quot;&gt;Closing Thoughts&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seriously loving my time in California. The weather is just soooo nice compared to the shithole of NYC weather. I probably won’t live here until I’m like 40 though, this place makes me want to chill, vibe, and get absolutely nothing productive done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;A bit of a tangent, but I think people my age and younger should travel solo more. I started with traveling solo to NYC (Manhattan for visiting friends and Brooklyn for work), then made my way up to going alone to Washington DC and Boston for conferences, and now the west coast far away from home. It’s been an amazing experience and you get the freedom to explore and meet new people! &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>William Zhang</name></author><summary type="html">On July 14th, I hopped on a plane from Newark to San Diego and began my California adventures 1. I took an overnight bus from San Diego to San Francisco a couple of days later, and then took the BART to Berkeley where I stayed for 2 weeks. While at Berkeley, I went on a couple of day trips to nearby cities like Alameda and Oakland. I went back to San Francisco for a night before taking a plane to Santa Barbara, stayed there for a night and then took a bus to Los Angeles where I’m crashing for two nights before heading back to New York. A bit of a tangent, but I think people my age and younger should travel solo more. I started with traveling solo to NYC (Manhattan for visiting friends and Brooklyn for work), then made my way up to going alone to Washington DC and Boston for conferences, and now the west coast far away from home. It’s been an amazing experience and you get the freedom to explore and meet new people! &amp;#8617;</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">FAQ-in-progress</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/faq-in-progress" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="FAQ-in-progress" /><published>2022-05-04T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-05-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/faq-in-progress</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/faq-in-progress">&lt;p&gt;I’ve been getting a lot of questions about research, startups, etc. lately, so I figured I would post an FAQ of sorts. If you’re young, motivated, ambitious, etc. and reached out asking a question, chances are I sent you this blog post. Enjoy :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, please introduced yourself to me when DMing or emailing, I want to know your story/background!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;frequently-asked-questions&quot;&gt;Frequently Asked Questions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q: &lt;strong&gt;How did you get software engineering positions with startups?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: I applied to summer internships in spring 2020 after winning a big Google competition, so my “resume” probably passed the initial screening. I was also decent at competitive programming so I could pass the technical interviews. After I landed my first position, new opportunities for startup work frequently popped up through my network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Q: &lt;strong&gt;How did you get a research position with MIT CSAIL?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: Quite a tale. A former intern at a company I was interviewing with was going to MIT for grad school. He encouraged me to reach out to his advisor, who was the director of the PRIMES computer science research track. I was connected with my mentor through that interaction, and had a very rewarding research experience! The moral of the story is to leverage your network; serendipitous, amazing things will happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Q: &lt;strong&gt;How did you get hired/published/awarded?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: Lots of passion, perseverance, and a dash of luck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Q: &lt;strong&gt;Could you connect me with &amp;lt;insert person/organization/opportunity here&amp;gt;?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: If we’ve been well-connected and have known each other for a bit, of course!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Q: &lt;strong&gt;Could you give me some tips for high school?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: Yes, read my high school &lt;a href=&quot;/posts/high-school-reflections.html&quot;&gt;reflections&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Q: &lt;strong&gt;How did you get into programming so young?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: So I wasn’t programming at age 5, but I think I got into video game development in Scratch when I was 10 and taught myself how to code (Python) a couple years after that. After that, I did competitive programming, and then open source development, and then startup/research stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Q: &lt;strong&gt;“How are you so cool?”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: 🦧&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>William Zhang</name></author><summary type="html">I’ve been getting a lot of questions about research, startups, etc. lately, so I figured I would post an FAQ of sorts. If you’re young, motivated, ambitious, etc. and reached out asking a question, chances are I sent you this blog post. Enjoy :)</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">High School Reflections</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/high-school-reflections" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="High School Reflections" /><published>2022-04-14T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-04-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/high-school-reflections</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/high-school-reflections">&lt;p&gt;It’s hard to believe that I’m going to be graduating high school in a couple of months. I have so many thoughts floating around in my head - as of late, I’ve tried to clear my commitments so I get some time in between now and summertime to take it slow and reflect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;senior-year-and-my-high-school-mentality&quot;&gt;Senior Year and My High School Mentality&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m really happy with how my senior year and overall high school mentality (at least my upperclassmen years) left me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In freshman and sophomore year (before COVID started), I was more or less following the crowd of my academically-motivated peers with a heavy school workload. I studied a ton and didn’t even have a lunch period. Looking back, I’m honestly amazed how I handled that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After COVID hit and school went remote, I had the time and freedom to pursue what I was really interested in. Piggybacking off of winning an international computer science award, I was able to land awesome opportunities working at startups, researching, competing in cybersecurity, launching nonprofits, etc. all during quarantine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I kept the same mentality during junior year. My school (public school in NY) gave us the option of taking the year completely virtually, and I jumped at the opportunity to do so. I was able to do so much cool shit (work, research, get 8+ hrs of sleep a night and wake up at 7AM for the 7:05AM start) while just having a Google Meet playing in the background.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m grateful to be back in person during my senior year. Although I’m MUCH less productive (ironically), I really enjoy spending the last year with my friends and classmates. I dropped Spanish and History, have so many free periods and chill classes - it’s great! I kinda feel bad for some (most) of my friends who still are grinding grades and furiously studying, but to each their own I guess. I’m relaxed putting less effort into grades and more into what I’m passionate about. I can sleep 7-8 hrs a night easily, and overall I’m just less stressed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second semester senioritis has hit me hard, but I’m embracing it. I got my first B’s and C’s last quarter, but I have good grades in my first two quarters to balance it out - &lt;em&gt;colleges pls don’t rescind me thx :)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;college&quot;&gt;College&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve gotten into a handful of great schools, and as of now I’m most likely going to be committing to Harvard c/o 2026.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going into college application season as an Asian-American male from New York gunning for computer science, let’s just say the demographics were not in my favor. Nevertheless, I decided not to do what some other people I know did, which is applying to a less competitive major in the hopes of transferring to CS. Taking a gap year(s) and not going to college altogether were all possibilities I was considering. In the end, I decided to apply to 5 schools early (Stanford + 4 state schools) and get it over with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In mid-December, I got rejected by Stanford’s restrictive early action program. This was a giant wake up call - humbly, I thought I had a great shot of going there. In a frenzied panic fueled by my fellow classmates’ early action/decision rejections and deferrals, I added 10 schools to my college list and decided to grind them over winter break.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It just so happened that during winter break my parents decided to take the entire family to Texas. I promptly caught COVID and was completely clonked out. I spent a grueling week high off my ass with cough drops, Tylenol, and the sorest throat possibly imaginable. During that time, I pretty much just wrote whatever came out my head for those college supplementals and submitted them right then and there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going into January I got into UIUC/Georgia Tech (CS), which I was happy about. However, in February and early-mid March I got deferred =&amp;gt; waitlisted at UMich, rejected from UCSD CS, waitlisted at both MIT (which I literally did research and published a first-author paper with!!) and CMU, and rejected from Berkeley. At this point I thought Georgia Tech (my top choice) wasn’t really worth it, and I was just going to skip college and go directly into industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, on Ivy Day (March 31st) I was pleasantly surprised. Here’s a rundown of my results:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;acceptances&quot;&gt;Acceptances&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Harvard&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yale&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Columbia&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Georgia Tech (CS)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;UIUC (CS)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;UMD (Undeclared =&amp;gt; rejected CS)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;UCSD (Undeclared =&amp;gt; rejected CS)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;waitlists&quot;&gt;Waitlists&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MIT&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CMU (CS)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cornell&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Princeton&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;UPenn&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Duke&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;UMich&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;rejections&quot;&gt;Rejections&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stanford&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Berkeley&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;thoughts&quot;&gt;Thoughts&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main selling point of college for me is just to hang out, make new friends/connections, and be exposed to more opportunities. I mean, it’s not like the binary search algorithm taught at a community college is going to be any different than the binary search algorithm taught at Harvard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What makes top colleges stand out is simply the talent density; having so many young ambitious people living together allows for amazing things to happen. It’s important to note that talent density isn’t only limited to college. Joining a startup, working at a nonprofit, etc. are all valuable ways to be exposed to these networks. However, I think compared to the alternatives, college in general is still the place with the strongest sense of community, camaraderie, and free will - students are working on bettering themselves rather than bettering the companies they work for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, for deciding what to do after high school, I think the most important question is whether or not the community and talent density at the school you want to go to outweighs the talent density at another endeavour (startup, nonprofit, etc.), factoring in the cost of college.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used to be quite anti-college, however upon talking to so many students at Harvard and other top schools, I’m quite excited to immerse myself in these environments. If you think about it, it’s truly the only time in your life you will be so closely subject to different cultures, viewpoints, and ways of thought on a daily basis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, I’m planning on concentrating in CS and taking a relatively easy workload so I have time to socialize, time to sleep, and time to myself. I know I can work, research, create a startup, etc. whenever I want. I want to give college a shot before throwing that opportunity away. After all, I can always drop out if I believe what I’m building can’t wait until graduation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Addendum:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regarding gap years, I totally support them. I was originally planning on working in the Bay for a year to establish California residency (because I thought I was gonna get into UC Berkeley’s MET program, silly me); that plan went out the window. However, now I’m really excited to go to college and meet new people, which is why there’s really no need for me to take a gap year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;advice&quot;&gt;Advice&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Am I qualified to give advice? I’ve gotten a lot of cold DMs on Twitter and emails about advice, wanting to call/chat, etc. Maybe I’ll direct some to this post. With further ado, here’s some of my tips for young, smart, motivated high schoolers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don’t spend too much time on academics (grades, classes, etc.). Law of diminishing returns - obviously take “hard” classes, but if it gets to a point where you are spending significant amounts of time studying and staying up late because of academics, it probably isn’t worth it.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;I just realized I didn’t talk about grades or test scores at all - go figure. I was able to coast by most classes with an A, got 5s on the APs and ~1500 on the SAT.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;I hate studying (maybe I should write another blog post on why studying for tests and shit is completely useless in the long run), so honestly if you can do decently great on tests with little or no studying you’re in an amazing position. That being said, I didn’t just “not study” throughout high school. I wish I could’ve done that, but I did a fair amount of “learning the unit right before the exam”.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do what you love. If you don’t know what your “passion” is, then spend meaningful time finding it. Don’t just fall into the workaholic academic hellhole to distract yourself. I’m sure most people reading this post, however, have got this tip figured out already.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BE ACTIVE AND HEALTHY&lt;/strong&gt;. Nobody likes a couch potato. Work out. Run. Lift. Go outside. Touch grass. Eat your protein.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Some generic tips that I still like:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Find communities.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Do competitions.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Work.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Connect with likeminded peers.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Don’t be afraid of failure or rejection.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to my good friend &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.uzpg.me/&quot;&gt;Uzay Girit&lt;/a&gt; for reading and reviewing this post.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>William Zhang</name></author><summary type="html">It’s hard to believe that I’m going to be graduating high school in a couple of months. I have so many thoughts floating around in my head - as of late, I’ve tried to clear my commitments so I get some time in between now and summertime to take it slow and reflect.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Twitter ENS Analysis</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/twitter-ens-analysis" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Twitter ENS Analysis" /><published>2022-03-13T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-03-13T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/twitter-ens-analysis</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/twitter-ens-analysis">&lt;p&gt;There’s a lot of fishy stuff going on in the crypto/web3 space, which prompted me to wonder, “What percentage of .eth Twitter handles/names actually resolve to an address?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This weekend, I found out. Here’s how.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TLDR: depending on the user category, anywhere ranging from 2-10% of domains DON’T resolve to an address.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;setup&quot;&gt;Setup&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The basics are pretty simple. We want to scrape Twitter profiles with ‘.eth’ domains, and lookup if these domains resolve to an address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To scrape Twitter profiles, I used the Twitter API (have a developer account from an old project that I still need to port over the blog post for) and the Tweepy wrapper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t think there’s an API for ENS lookups, so I just performed a rate-limited GET request to etherscan’s ENS lookup tool with a believable user agent and parsed the return HTML.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Results were written to a file and then parsed/analyzed later. The scripts took around an hour to code, mainly due to fiddling around with rate limits and Twitter’s search queries. The runtime of the scrape job was around 6 hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;results&quot;&gt;Results&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A total of 2853 users were sampled across different categories such as art and NFTs. Here’s a breakdown of the basic statistics:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Category&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Total&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Invalid&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Percentage&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Population&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2853&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;141&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;4.94%&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;General&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;872&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;18&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2.06%&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Art&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;786&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;51&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;6.49%&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;NFT&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;479&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;46&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;9.6%&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;DAO&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;716&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;26&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;3.63%&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Side note: bro why does this Jekyll theme produce such terrible tables? If anyone wants to help me fix the spacing lmk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See the code and some more graphs (follower/following data) on Github &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/WilliamHYZhang/Twitter-ENS-Analysis&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-does-this-mean&quot;&gt;What Does This Mean?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m interested how invalid ENS domains relate to web2.0 link rot. It’s cool that the population 4.94% of invalid .eth domains is quite close to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/21/22447690/link-rot-research-new-york-times-domain-hijacking&quot;&gt;6% of inaccessible links from 2018 sources&lt;/a&gt; (around the same time as the start of ENS).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that we can treat this invalid .eth domain percentage as a measure of the maturity of a certain sector of the crypto world. A user having an invalid .eth domain either means they lack the intellect to configure their domain correctly, the domain expired, or (most likely) they are simply obliviously buying into the crypto hype. For example, I mean just &lt;em&gt;look&lt;/em&gt; at the NFT invalid link percentage (~10%). Yeah, I’m not getting involved in that shit anytime soon. On the other hand, I’m impressed at the “maturity” of DAOs, they seem to be pretty nice (I don’t think I’ll fall for a DAO scam).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;limitations&quot;&gt;Limitations&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Twitter only surfaces the top 1000 accounts given a search query, which results in massively popular accounts being returned first. This is why the “General” category with only an ‘.eth’ query had such a low percentage of invalid domains. Adding specific categories helped reduce this bias towards popular accounts. Nevertheless, I believe the true percentages across all categories are probably a couple points higher.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The regex for domain search should also be matching against dashes.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In hindsight I realize that these categories are likely to be non-disjoint, so the set I used to prevent duplicates across categories should probably be removed.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Kicking myself for not exporting as a CSV in the scrape job instead of crapping out a text file.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Apparently ‘$’ is an invalid Twitter query, but I’m not running that 6 hour scrape job again.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If anyone wants to address these limitations or just make this analysis and data collection process more robust, feel free to open up a PR on my repo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways, this was a pretty neat project. I was honestly expecting the percentage of invalid links to be significantly higher. I’m not a full ETH bullhead; although I 100% believe in the cryptography and technical research towards the blockchain, there are a bunch of dubious projects and grossly inaccurate buzzword usage (cough cough zkSNARKs) over the media that make me skeptical. It was a pleasant surprise that most domains were real!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>William Zhang</name></author><summary type="html">There’s a lot of fishy stuff going on in the crypto/web3 space, which prompted me to wonder, “What percentage of .eth Twitter handles/names actually resolve to an address?”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Successes and Failures</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/successes-and-failures" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Successes and Failures" /><published>2022-02-18T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-02-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/successes-and-failures</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/successes-and-failures">&lt;p&gt;In order to chase success, we have to face failure along the way. Here’s a look into my journey so far. I think it’s important to share this because it highlights the impact of ambition. To me, successes and failures are just consequences of taking meaningful risks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll try and keep this up-to-date, but this list is very much non-comprehensive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last Updated: Feb. 18, 2022&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;successes&quot;&gt;Successes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;2022&quot;&gt;2022&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Named a Regeneron STS Scholar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hydra wins the Best Paper Award from IEEE&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Accepted into some schools&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Landed a consulting gig with a crypto startup&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Got back to engineering at Clay&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2021&quot;&gt;2021&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Founded the Hydra project: invented verifiable compute protocols, built out the framework, wrote a manuscript, got it published and raised grant funding from Emergent Ventures&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;First expenses-paid trips to Washington DC, Boston, and upstate NY for conferences and retreats&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Got to meet amazing researchers, entrepreneurs, and VCs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Built out complete authentication and security infrastructure at Clay&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hired as an instructor for machine learning and advanced computer science&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Won a couple of programming awards&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Kicked out of all-you-can-eat sushi for eating too much :)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2020&quot;&gt;2020&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Named the Google Code-in Grand Prize Winner for TensorFlow&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;First software engineering internship at Clay after a handful of applications and interviews&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Landed contracting gig with crypto startup&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Landed research position with MIT CSAIL&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Founding member of RGBsec and later joined Pwnzorz, internationally ranked in cybersecurity CTFs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Started contributing to Mathisi-fy, raised funding and organized hackathons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;failures&quot;&gt;Failures&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;2022-1&quot;&gt;2022&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Suffering from major senioritis in academics&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Deferred and rejected from schools&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Failed to advance to the second round of a REGIONAL science fair&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Devolved to the mind-state of a jellyfish during school hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2021-1&quot;&gt;2021&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rejected from a school&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rejected from scholarships&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rejected from MIT PRIMES and RSI&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hydra rejected from ACM and IEEE conference&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rejected from OxPARC’s ZK workshop&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Decided not to pursue working with a well-funded crypto startup I would’ve had major equity in&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Started to become a down bad couch potato (not anymore)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2020-1&quot;&gt;2020&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rejected after interviews with tech companies (trading firms, AI, SaaS)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dropped out of US Army-funded research program since I wasn’t interested in it&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Research was scooped just before publication&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post is inspired by a couple of personal pages, including websites by &lt;a href=&quot;https://calix.dev/blog/failures&quot;&gt;Calix Huang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.katmh.com/fail&quot;&gt;Kat Huang&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://jzhao.xyz/posts/a-failure-resume/&quot;&gt;Jacky Zhao&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>William Zhang</name></author><summary type="html">In order to chase success, we have to face failure along the way. Here’s a look into my journey so far. I think it’s important to share this because it highlights the impact of ambition. To me, successes and failures are just consequences of taking meaningful risks. I’ll try and keep this up-to-date, but this list is very much non-comprehensive. Last Updated: Feb. 18, 2022 Successes 2022 Named a Regeneron STS Scholar Hydra wins the Best Paper Award from IEEE Accepted into some schools Landed a consulting gig with a crypto startup Got back to engineering at Clay 2021 Founded the Hydra project: invented verifiable compute protocols, built out the framework, wrote a manuscript, got it published and raised grant funding from Emergent Ventures First expenses-paid trips to Washington DC, Boston, and upstate NY for conferences and retreats Got to meet amazing researchers, entrepreneurs, and VCs Built out complete authentication and security infrastructure at Clay Hired as an instructor for machine learning and advanced computer science Won a couple of programming awards Kicked out of all-you-can-eat sushi for eating too much :) 2020 Named the Google Code-in Grand Prize Winner for TensorFlow First software engineering internship at Clay after a handful of applications and interviews Landed contracting gig with crypto startup Landed research position with MIT CSAIL Founding member of RGBsec and later joined Pwnzorz, internationally ranked in cybersecurity CTFs Started contributing to Mathisi-fy, raised funding and organized hackathons Failures 2022 Suffering from major senioritis in academics Deferred and rejected from schools Failed to advance to the second round of a REGIONAL science fair Devolved to the mind-state of a jellyfish during school hours 2021 Rejected from a school Rejected from scholarships Rejected from MIT PRIMES and RSI Hydra rejected from ACM and IEEE conference Rejected from OxPARC’s ZK workshop Decided not to pursue working with a well-funded crypto startup I would’ve had major equity in Started to become a down bad couch potato (not anymore) 2020 Rejected after interviews with tech companies (trading firms, AI, SaaS) Dropped out of US Army-funded research program since I wasn’t interested in it Research was scooped just before publication This post is inspired by a couple of personal pages, including websites by Calix Huang, Kat Huang, and Jacky Zhao.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Twitter Giveaway Bot</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/twitter-giveaway-bot" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Twitter Giveaway Bot" /><published>2021-02-27T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-02-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/twitter-giveaway-bot</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/twitter-giveaway-bot">&lt;p&gt;Way back when in late 2019, I became aware of this absolute genius of a man through a DefCon YouTube video &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iAOOdYsK7MM&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; who essentially used Twitter’s API to enter every single Twitter giveaway on the platform, and he ended up winning some pretty cool stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That year I built out a program, registered for a Twitter dev account “for educational purposes” and all that jazz, and I think in two weeks or so got banned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways, I came back to it over the past winter break and was determined to make it better. I think it took a couple hours to just revamp that old
code and make sure I wasn’t at risk of getting banned again. Previously I had it running on my regular computer, but now I have an old Dell
desktop that I configured to be run as a Linux server so the code is just running there now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some notes about what I had changed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No more follower churn/queue, mainly because it was too risky.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Same thing with likes, I removed the liking feature entirely since I’m pretty sure that’s why I got banned last time.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Limited following.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And finally, probably the most big brain move. To maintain a healthy following/follower ratio, I now farm follows by tweeting “giveaway-like” tweets every so often, and have bots that OTHER people create like, follow, and retweet :))&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And yeah, that’s pretty much it. I’ve mostly won some small stuff like Pokemon codes, Roblox stuff, and other video game prizes that I’m too lazy to claim but I check in with it every once it a while. Check out the bot in action &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/LuckyWillyV2&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Addendum: April 14th, 2022&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally ported over this old blog post with a couple of edits. Unfortunately, @LuckyWillyV2 is no longer active because I don’t have enough ethernet connections to support my server. Check out highly outdated code &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/WilliamHYZhang/Twitter-Giveaway-Bot&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fun fact: I talked about this project on one of my Harvard supplemental essays!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>William Zhang</name></author><summary type="html">Way back when in late 2019, I became aware of this absolute genius of a man through a DefCon YouTube video here who essentially used Twitter’s API to enter every single Twitter giveaway on the platform, and he ended up winning some pretty cool stuff.</summary></entry></feed>