<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-05-09T16:06:49-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">William Zhang</title><subtitle>Personal Website</subtitle><author><name>William Zhang</name></author><entry><title type="html">FAQ-in-progress</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/ambitious-youngling-faq" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="FAQ-in-progress" /><published>2022-05-04T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-05-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/ambitious-youngling-faq</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/ambitious-youngling-faq">&lt;p&gt;I’ve been getting a lot of questions about research, startups, etc. lately, so I figured I would post an FAQ of sorts. If you’re young, motivated, ambitious, etc. and reached out asking a question, chances are I sent you this blog post. Enjoy :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, please introduced yourself to me when DMing or emailing, I want to know your story/background!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;frequently-asked-questions&quot;&gt;Frequently Asked Questions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q: &lt;strong&gt;How did you get software engineering positions with startups?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: I applied to summer internships in spring 2020 after winning a big Google competition, so my “resume” probably passed the initial screening. I was also decent at competitive programming so I could pass the technical interviews. After I landed my first position, new opportunities for startup work frequently popped up through my network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Q: &lt;strong&gt;How did you get a research position with MIT CSAIL?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: Quite a tale. A former intern at a company I was interviewing with was going to MIT for grad school. He encouraged me to reach out to his advisor, who was the director of the PRIMES computer science research track. I was connected with my mentor through that interaction, and had a very rewarding research experience! The moral of the story is to leverage your network; serendipitous, amazing things will happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Q: &lt;strong&gt;How did you get hired/published/awarded?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: Lots of passion, perseverance, and a dash of luck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Q: &lt;strong&gt;Could you connect me with &amp;lt;insert person/organization/opportunity here&amp;gt;?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: If we’ve been well-connected and have known each other for a bit, of course!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Q: &lt;strong&gt;Could you give me some tips for high school?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: Yes, read my high school &lt;a href=&quot;/posts/high-school-reflections.html&quot;&gt;reflections&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Q: &lt;strong&gt;How did you get into programming so young?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: So I wasn’t programming at age 5, but I think I got into video game development in Scratch when I was 10 and taught myself how to code (Python) a couple years after that. After that, I did competitive programming, and then open source development, and then startup/research stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Q: &lt;strong&gt;“How are you so cool?”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: 🦧&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>William Zhang</name></author><summary type="html">I’ve been getting a lot of questions about research, startups, etc. lately, so I figured I would post an FAQ of sorts. If you’re young, motivated, ambitious, etc. and reached out asking a question, chances are I sent you this blog post. Enjoy :)</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">High School Reflections</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/high-school-reflections" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="High School Reflections" /><published>2022-04-14T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-04-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/high-school-reflections</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/high-school-reflections">&lt;p&gt;It’s hard to believe that I’m going to be graduating high school in a couple of months. I have so many thoughts floating around in my head - as of late, I’ve tried to clear my commitments so I get some time in between now and summertime to take it slow and reflect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;senior-year-and-my-high-school-mentality&quot;&gt;Senior Year and My High School Mentality&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m really happy with how my senior year and overall high school mentality (at least my upperclassmen years) left me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In freshman and sophomore year (before COVID started), I was more or less following the crowd of my academically-motivated peers with a heavy school workload. I studied a ton and didn’t even have a lunch period. Looking back, I’m honestly amazed how I handled that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After COVID hit and school went remote, I had the time and freedom to pursue what I was really interested in. Piggybacking off of winning an international computer science award, I was able to land awesome opportunities working at startups, researching, competing in cybersecurity, launching nonprofits, etc. all during quarantine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I kept the same mentality during junior year. My school (public school in NY) gave us the option of taking the year completely virtually, and I jumped at the opportunity to do so. I was able to do so much cool shit (work, research, get 8+ hrs of sleep a night and wake up at 7AM for the 7:05AM start) while just having a Google Meet playing in the background.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m grateful to be back in person during my senior year. Although I’m MUCH less productive (ironically), I really enjoy spending the last year with my friends and classmates. I dropped Spanish and History, have so many free periods and chill classes - it’s great! I kinda feel bad for some (most) of my friends who still are grinding grades and furiously studying, but to each their own I guess. I’m relaxed putting less effort into grades and more into what I’m passionate about. I can sleep 7-8 hrs a night easily, and overall I’m just less stressed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second semester senioritis has hit me hard, but I’m embracing it. I got my first B’s and C’s last quarter, but I have good grades in my first two quarters to balance it out - &lt;em&gt;colleges pls don’t rescind me thx :)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;college&quot;&gt;College&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve gotten into a handful of great schools, and as of now I’m most likely going to be committing to Harvard c/o 2026.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going into college application season as an Asian-American male from New York gunning for computer science, let’s just say the demographics were not in my favor. Nevertheless, I decided not to do what some other people I know did, which is applying to a less competitive major in the hopes of transferring to CS. Taking a gap year(s) and not going to college altogether were all possibilities I was considering. In the end, I decided to apply to 5 schools early (Stanford + 4 state schools) and get it over with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In mid-December, I got rejected by Stanford’s restrictive early action program. This was a giant wake up call - humbly, I thought I had a great shot of going there. In a frenzied panic fueled by my fellow classmates’ early action/decision rejections and deferrals, I added 10 schools to my college list and decided to grind them over winter break.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It just so happened that during winter break my parents decided to take the entire family to Texas. I promptly caught COVID and was completely clonked out. I spent a grueling week high off my ass with cough drops, Tylenol, and the sorest throat possibly imaginable. During that time, I pretty much just wrote whatever came out my head for those college supplementals and submitted them right then and there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going into January I got into UIUC/Georgia Tech (CS), which I was happy about. However, in February and early-mid March I got deferred =&amp;gt; waitlisted at UMich, rejected from UCSD CS, waitlisted at both MIT (which I literally did research and published a first-author paper with!!) and CMU, and rejected from Berkeley. At this point I thought Georgia Tech (my top choice) wasn’t really worth it, and I was just going to skip college and go directly into industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, on Ivy Day (March 31st) I was pleasantly surprised. Here’s a rundown of my results:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;acceptances&quot;&gt;Acceptances&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Harvard&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yale&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Columbia&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Georgia Tech (CS)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;UIUC (CS)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;UMD (Undeclared =&amp;gt; rejected CS)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;UCSD (Undeclared =&amp;gt; rejected CS)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;waitlists&quot;&gt;Waitlists&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MIT&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CMU (CS)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cornell&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Princeton&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;UPenn&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Duke&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;UMich&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;rejections&quot;&gt;Rejections&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stanford&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Berkeley&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;thoughts&quot;&gt;Thoughts&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main selling point of college for me is just to hang out, make new friends/connections, and be exposed to more opportunities. I mean, it’s not like the binary search algorithm taught at a community college is going to be any different than the binary search algorithm taught at Harvard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What makes top colleges stand out is simply the talent density; having so many young ambitious people living together allows for amazing things to happen. It’s important to note that talent density isn’t only limited to college. Joining a startup, working at a nonprofit, etc. are all valuable ways to be exposed to these networks. However, I think compared to the alternatives, college in general is still the place with the strongest sense of community, camaraderie, and free will - students are working on bettering themselves rather than bettering the companies they work for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, for deciding what to do after high school, I think the most important question is whether or not the community and talent density at the school you want to go to outweighs the talent density at another endeavour (startup, nonprofit, etc.), factoring in the cost of college.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used to be quite anti-college, however upon talking to so many students at Harvard and other top schools, I’m quite excited to immerse myself in these environments. If you think about it, it’s truly the only time in your life you will be so closely subject to different cultures, viewpoints, and ways of thought on a daily basis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, I’m planning on concentrating in CS and taking a relatively easy workload so I have time to socialize, time to sleep, and time to myself. I know I can work, research, create a startup, etc. whenever I want. I want to give college a shot before throwing that opportunity away. After all, I can always drop out if I believe what I’m building can’t wait until graduation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Addendum:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regarding gap years, I totally support them. I was originally planning on working in the Bay for a year to establish California residency (because I thought I was gonna get into UC Berkeley’s MET program, silly me); that plan went out the window. However, now I’m really excited to go to college and meet new people, which is why there’s really no need for me to take a gap year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;advice&quot;&gt;Advice&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Am I qualified to give advice? I’ve gotten a lot of cold DMs on Twitter and emails about advice, wanting to call/chat, etc. Maybe I’ll direct some to this post. With further ado, here’s some of my tips for young, smart, motivated high schoolers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don’t spend too much time on academics (grades, classes, etc.). Law of diminishing returns - obviously take “hard” classes, but if it gets to a point where you are spending significant amounts of time studying and staying up late because of academics, it probably isn’t worth it.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;I just realized I didn’t talk about grades or test scores at all - go figure. I was able to coast by most classes with an A, got 5s on the APs and ~1500 on the SAT.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;I hate studying (maybe I should write another blog post on why studying for tests and shit is completely useless in the long run), so honestly if you can do decently great on tests with little or no studying you’re in an amazing position. That being said, I didn’t just “not study” throughout high school. I wish I could’ve done that, but I did a fair amount of “learning the unit right before the exam”.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do what you love. If you don’t know what your “passion” is, then spend meaningful time finding it. Don’t just fall into the workaholic academic hellhole to distract yourself. I’m sure most people reading this post, however, have got this tip figured out already.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BE ACTIVE AND HEALTHY&lt;/strong&gt;. Nobody likes a couch potato. Work out. Run. Lift. Go outside. Touch grass. Eat your protein.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Some generic tips that I still like:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Find communities.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Do competitions.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Work.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Connect with likeminded peers.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Don’t be afraid of failure or rejection.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to my good friend &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.uzpg.me/&quot;&gt;Uzay Girit&lt;/a&gt; for reading and reviewing this post.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>William Zhang</name></author><summary type="html">It’s hard to believe that I’m going to be graduating high school in a couple of months. I have so many thoughts floating around in my head - as of late, I’ve tried to clear my commitments so I get some time in between now and summertime to take it slow and reflect.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Twitter ENS Analysis</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/twitter-ens-analysis" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Twitter ENS Analysis" /><published>2022-03-13T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-03-13T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/twitter-ens-analysis</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/twitter-ens-analysis">&lt;p&gt;There’s a lot of fishy stuff going on in the crypto/web3 space, which prompted me to wonder, “What percentage of .eth Twitter handles/names actually resolve to an address?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This weekend, I found out. Here’s how.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TLDR: depending on the user category, anywhere ranging from 2-10% of domains DON’T resolve to an address.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;setup&quot;&gt;Setup&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The basics are pretty simple. We want to scrape Twitter profiles with ‘.eth’ domains, and lookup if these domains resolve to an address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To scrape Twitter profiles, I used the Twitter API (have a developer account from an old project that I still need to port over the blog post for) and the Tweepy wrapper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t think there’s an API for ENS lookups, so I just performed a rate-limited GET request to etherscan’s ENS lookup tool with a believable user agent and parsed the return HTML.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Results were written to a file and then parsed/analyzed later. The scripts took around an hour to code, mainly due to fiddling around with rate limits and Twitter’s search queries. The runtime of the scrape job was around 6 hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;results&quot;&gt;Results&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A total of 2853 users were sampled across different categories such as art and NFTs. Here’s a breakdown of the basic statistics:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Category&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Total&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Invalid&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Percentage&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Population&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2853&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;141&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;4.94%&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;General&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;872&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;18&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2.06%&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Art&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;786&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;51&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;6.49%&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;NFT&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;479&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;46&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;9.6%&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;DAO&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;716&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;26&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;3.63%&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Side note: bro why does this Jekyll theme produce such terrible tables? If anyone wants to help me fix the spacing lmk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See the code and some more graphs (follower/following data) on Github &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/WilliamHYZhang/Twitter-ENS-Analysis&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-does-this-mean&quot;&gt;What Does This Mean?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m interested how invalid ENS domains relate to web2.0 link rot. It’s cool that the population 4.94% of invalid .eth domains is quite close to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/21/22447690/link-rot-research-new-york-times-domain-hijacking&quot;&gt;6% of inaccessible links from 2018 sources&lt;/a&gt; (around the same time as the start of ENS).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that we can treat this invalid .eth domain percentage as a measure of the maturity of a certain sector of the crypto world. A user having an invalid .eth domain either means they lack the intellect to configure their domain correctly, the domain expired, or (most likely) they are simply obliviously buying into the crypto hype. For example, I mean just &lt;em&gt;look&lt;/em&gt; at the NFT invalid link percentage (~10%). Yeah, I’m not getting involved in that shit anytime soon. On the other hand, I’m impressed at the “maturity” of DAOs, they seem to be pretty nice (I don’t think I’ll fall for a DAO scam).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;limitations&quot;&gt;Limitations&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Twitter only surfaces the top 1000 accounts given a search query, which results in massively popular accounts being returned first. This is why the “General” category with only an ‘.eth’ query had such a low percentage of invalid domains. Adding specific categories helped reduce this bias towards popular accounts. Nevertheless, I believe the true percentages across all categories are probably a couple points higher.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The regex for domain search should also be matching against dashes.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In hindsight I realize that these categories are likely to be non-disjoint, so the set I used to prevent duplicates across categories should probably be removed.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Kicking myself for not exporting as a CSV in the scrape job instead of crapping out a text file.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Apparently ‘$’ is an invalid Twitter query, but I’m not running that 6 hour scrape job again.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If anyone wants to address these limitations or just make this analysis and data collection process more robust, feel free to open up a PR on my repo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways, this was a pretty neat project. I was honestly expecting the percentage of invalid links to be significantly higher. I’m not a full ETH bullhead; although I 100% believe in the cryptography and technical research towards the blockchain, there are a bunch of dubious projects and grossly inaccurate buzzword usage (cough cough zkSNARKs) over the media that make me skeptical. It was a pleasant surprise that most domains were real!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>William Zhang</name></author><summary type="html">There’s a lot of fishy stuff going on in the crypto/web3 space, which prompted me to wonder, “What percentage of .eth Twitter handles/names actually resolve to an address?”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Successes and Failures</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/successes-and-failures" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Successes and Failures" /><published>2022-02-18T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-02-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/successes-and-failures</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/successes-and-failures">&lt;p&gt;In order to chase success, we have to face failure along the way. Here’s a look into my journey so far. I think it’s important to share this because it highlights the impact of ambition. To me, successes and failures are just consequences of taking meaningful risks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll try and keep this up-to-date, but this list is very much non-comprehensive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last Updated: Feb. 18, 2022&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;successes&quot;&gt;Successes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;2022&quot;&gt;2022&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Named a Regeneron STS Scholar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hydra wins the Best Paper Award from IEEE&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Accepted into some schools&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Landed a consulting gig with a crypto startup&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Got back to engineering at Clay&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2021&quot;&gt;2021&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Founded the Hydra project: invented verifiable compute protocols, built out the framework, wrote a manuscript, got it published and raised grant funding from Emergent Ventures&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;First expenses-paid trips to Washington DC, Boston, and upstate NY for conferences and retreats&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Got to meet amazing researchers, entrepreneurs, and VCs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Built out complete authentication and security infrastructure at Clay&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hired as an instructor for machine learning and advanced computer science&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Won a couple of programming awards&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Kicked out of all-you-can-eat sushi for eating too much :)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2020&quot;&gt;2020&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Named the Google Code-in Grand Prize Winner for TensorFlow&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;First software engineering internship at Clay after a handful of applications and interviews&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Landed contracting gig with crypto startup&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Landed research position with MIT CSAIL&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Founding member of RGBsec and later joined Pwnzorz, internationally ranked in cybersecurity CTFs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Started contributing to Mathisi-fy, raised funding and organized hackathons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;failures&quot;&gt;Failures&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;2022-1&quot;&gt;2022&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Suffering from major senioritis in academics&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Deferred and rejected from schools&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Failed to advance to the second round of a REGIONAL science fair&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Devolved to the mind-state of a jellyfish during school hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2021-1&quot;&gt;2021&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rejected from a school&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rejected from scholarships&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rejected from MIT PRIMES and RSI&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hydra rejected from ACM and IEEE conference&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rejected from OxPARC’s ZK workshop&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Decided not to pursue working with a well-funded crypto startup I would’ve had major equity in&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Started to become a down bad couch potato (not anymore)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2020-1&quot;&gt;2020&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rejected after interviews with tech companies (trading firms, AI, SaaS)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dropped out of US Army-funded research program since I wasn’t interested in it&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Research was scooped just before publication&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post is inspired by a couple of personal pages, including websites by &lt;a href=&quot;https://calix.dev/blog/failures&quot;&gt;Calix Huang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.katmh.com/fail&quot;&gt;Kat Huang&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://jzhao.xyz/posts/a-failure-resume/&quot;&gt;Jacky Zhao&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>William Zhang</name></author><summary type="html">In order to chase success, we have to face failure along the way. Here’s a look into my journey so far. I think it’s important to share this because it highlights the impact of ambition. To me, successes and failures are just consequences of taking meaningful risks. I’ll try and keep this up-to-date, but this list is very much non-comprehensive. Last Updated: Feb. 18, 2022 Successes 2022 Named a Regeneron STS Scholar Hydra wins the Best Paper Award from IEEE Accepted into some schools Landed a consulting gig with a crypto startup Got back to engineering at Clay 2021 Founded the Hydra project: invented verifiable compute protocols, built out the framework, wrote a manuscript, got it published and raised grant funding from Emergent Ventures First expenses-paid trips to Washington DC, Boston, and upstate NY for conferences and retreats Got to meet amazing researchers, entrepreneurs, and VCs Built out complete authentication and security infrastructure at Clay Hired as an instructor for machine learning and advanced computer science Won a couple of programming awards Kicked out of all-you-can-eat sushi for eating too much :) 2020 Named the Google Code-in Grand Prize Winner for TensorFlow First software engineering internship at Clay after a handful of applications and interviews Landed contracting gig with crypto startup Landed research position with MIT CSAIL Founding member of RGBsec and later joined Pwnzorz, internationally ranked in cybersecurity CTFs Started contributing to Mathisi-fy, raised funding and organized hackathons Failures 2022 Suffering from major senioritis in academics Deferred and rejected from schools Failed to advance to the second round of a REGIONAL science fair Devolved to the mind-state of a jellyfish during school hours 2021 Rejected from a school Rejected from scholarships Rejected from MIT PRIMES and RSI Hydra rejected from ACM and IEEE conference Rejected from OxPARC’s ZK workshop Decided not to pursue working with a well-funded crypto startup I would’ve had major equity in Started to become a down bad couch potato (not anymore) 2020 Rejected after interviews with tech companies (trading firms, AI, SaaS) Dropped out of US Army-funded research program since I wasn’t interested in it Research was scooped just before publication This post is inspired by a couple of personal pages, including websites by Calix Huang, Kat Huang, and Jacky Zhao.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Twitter Giveaway Bot</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/twitter-giveaway-bot" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Twitter Giveaway Bot" /><published>2021-02-27T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-02-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/twitter-giveaway-bot</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/twitter-giveaway-bot">&lt;p&gt;Way back when in late 2019, I became aware of this absolute genius of a man through a DefCon YouTube video &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iAOOdYsK7MM&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; who essentially used Twitter’s API to enter every single Twitter giveaway on the platform, and he ended up winning some pretty cool stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That year I built out a program, registered for a Twitter dev account “for educational purposes” and all that jazz, and I think in two weeks or so got banned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways, I came back to it over the past winter break and was determined to make it better. I think it took a couple hours to just revamp that old
code and make sure I wasn’t at risk of getting banned again. Previously I had it running on my regular computer, but now I have an old Dell
desktop that I configured to be run as a Linux server so the code is just running there now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some notes about what I had changed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No more follower churn/queue, mainly because it was too risky.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Same thing with likes, I removed the liking feature entirely since I’m pretty sure that’s why I got banned last time.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Limited following.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And finally, probably the most big brain move. To maintain a healthy following/follower ratio, I now farm follows by tweeting “giveaway-like” tweets every so often, and have bots that OTHER people create like, follow, and retweet :))&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And yeah, that’s pretty much it. I’ve mostly won some small stuff like Pokemon codes, Roblox stuff, and other video game prizes that I’m too lazy to claim but I check in with it every once it a while. Check out the bot in action &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/LuckyWillyV2&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Addendum: April 14th, 2022&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally ported over this old blog post with a couple of edits. Unfortunately, @LuckyWillyV2 is no longer active because I don’t have enough ethernet connections to support my server. Check out highly outdated code &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/WilliamHYZhang/Twitter-Giveaway-Bot&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fun fact: I talked about this project on one of my Harvard supplemental essays!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>William Zhang</name></author><summary type="html">Way back when in late 2019, I became aware of this absolute genius of a man through a DefCon YouTube video here who essentially used Twitter’s API to enter every single Twitter giveaway on the platform, and he ended up winning some pretty cool stuff.</summary></entry></feed>